<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog.atom"/>
  <title>VanGo Vapes - Blog</title>
  <updated>2021-04-09T16:57:26-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VanGo Vapes</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-history-of-cool-and-frozen-tropix</id>
    <published>2021-04-09T16:57:26-07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T16:57:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-history-of-cool-and-frozen-tropix"/>
    <title>The History Behind Cool and Frozen Tropix</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shawna Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Since being established in 2014, VanGo Vapes has prided itself on bringing nothing but the best in term of flavors. Each one is team tested and tweaked until the flavor matches the goal perfectly. <span style="color: #ff2a00;"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/house-of-fruit-blends/products/tropical-mint" title="Cool Tropix" style="color: #ff2a00;"><strong>Cool Tropix</strong></a></span> was one of the original 10 flavors created by VanGo. It is a fruity blend of <span style="color: #ffff00;"><strong>pineapple</strong></span>, <span style="color: #ff8000;"><strong>peach</strong></span>, and hints of <span style="color: #80ff00;"><strong>mint</strong></span>.</p>
<p>CEO Saadiq Daya says that his inspiration for this creation was his allergies. “ I have always loved pineapple, it is one of my favorite fruits. Early into my adult years I became allergic to it as well as many other <span style="color: #ff8000;"><strong>tropical fruits</strong></span>. This juice allows me to get the same flavors without actually eating the it!”</p>
<p>One of VanGo’s goals has always been to emphasize Flaving. The goal is not just to make e-juice but rather to create an experience. <span style="color: #ff2a00;"><strong><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/house-of-fruit-blends/products/tropical-mint" title="Cool Tropix" style="color: #ff2a00;">Cool Tropix</a></strong></span> hit the nail on the head for being the first <span style="color: #00aaff;"><strong>menthol</strong> </span>juice released by the team, but there quickly became interest for a juice that was colder. This is where <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-tropix" title="Frozen Tropix" style="color: #ff8000;"><strong>Frozen Tropix</strong></a> grew from.</p>
<p><span style="color: #ff8000;"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-tropix" title="Frozen Tropix" style="color: #ff8000;"><strong>Frozen Tropix</strong></a></span> is a tweaked spin off of the original Cool Tropix and it was released nearly two years later in 2016.</p>
<p>The difference between the two is that the <span style="color: #ff8000;"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-tropix" title="Frozen Tropix" style="color: #ff8000;"><strong>Frozen Tropix</strong></a></span> has an added hint of <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><strong>vanilla</strong> </span>and it is both <span style="color: #00aaff;"><strong>cooler</strong> </span>and <span style="color: #ff2a00;"><strong>sweeter</strong> </span>to vape! This juice quickly became Saadiq’s all day vape, and has continued to be his all day to this day. An interesting fact about <span style="color: #ff8000;"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-tropix" title="Frozen Tropix" style="color: #ff8000;"><strong>Frozen Tropix</strong></a></span> is that it is the only flavor to ever have been sold in 140ml with its own unique labels and packaging. It is certainly a one off and one that the entire VanGo team is extremely proud of.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/our-first-flavors-ever</id>
    <published>2021-02-12T15:41:35-08:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T15:45:41-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/our-first-flavors-ever"/>
    <title>Our First e-Juice Flavors - Ever!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Saabir Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>We are throwing it way back to 2014 when VanGo created their first 5 flavors! As an up-and-coming Vancouver e-juice company, the team knew that they wanted their product to be unique. The inspiration behind both the names and the flavor profiles for each juice was the desire to bring new and interesting juice to the vape market in Canada. The goal was to have a variety of different flavors in the line-up that would appeal to a wide variety of consumers.</span></p>
<p><span>Fruits, menthols, tobaccos, creams, and desserts were the categories that started it all. So, for all you loyal VanGo fam members who have been with us since the start, let us see if you can remember these classics.</span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<span style="color: #00aaff;"><strong>Albino</strong></span> – White grapes with undertones of blueberry and vanilla.</li>
<li>
<span style="color: #ff2a00;"><strong>Red Albino</strong></span> – A sweet raspberry and strawberry combined with white grapes.</li>
<li>
<span style="color: #80ff00;"><a href="vangovapes.com/products/soft-fuzz?_pos=1&amp;_sid=4a46058d2&amp;_ss=r" target="_blank" title="Soft Fuzz" style="color: #80ff00;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Soft Fuzz</strong></a></span> – A luscious blend of watermelon, peach and pineapple.</li>
<li>
<span style="color: #ff00ff;"><strong>Jelly Monkey</strong></span> – Ripe bananas blended together with raspberries and custard.</li>
<li>
<span style="color: #ff8000;"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/tropical-mint?_pos=1&amp;_sid=4dc1e3553&amp;_ss=r" target="_blank" title="Cool Tropix" style="color: #ff8000;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Cool Tropix</strong></a></span> – Tropical pineapple with tones of mint.</li>
</ol>
<p>In fact, Soft Fuzz and Cool Tropix are still being sold to this day! Check them out at the links below:</p>
<p><span style="color: #80ff00;"><a href="vangovapes.com/products/soft-fuzz?_pos=1&amp;_sid=4a46058d2&amp;_ss=r" target="_blank" title="Soft Fuzz" style="color: #80ff00;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Soft Fuzz</strong></a></span> - <span style="color: #ff8000;"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/tropical-mint?_pos=1&amp;_sid=4dc1e3553&amp;_ss=r" target="_blank" title="Cool Tropix" style="color: #ff8000;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Cool Tropix</strong></a></span></p>
<p><span>The feedback from these 5 was outstanding. Therefore, the team continued to release flavors continuously over the next 6 years. Not all the classics survived. Some have been dropped, rebranded, or tweaked… but nonetheless, they were the foundation of what now is a company with over 80 flavors!</span></p>
<p><span>The vaping industry has evolved rapidly over the years and it has been important to create a product that is meeting the demands of the consumer. CEO Saadiq Daya notes that it has been an interesting ride watching the way that the industry has changed and sometimes even coming back full circle. When VanGo first started creating flavors, they were designed for small units that could not handle much sweetener. As time went on, the devices got bigger and the importance of Flaving vs simply vaping started to grow. This is when the addition of sweetener in e-liquid became popular and VanGo created its flavors based on what the customers were wanting. </span></p>
<p><span>Now, NicSalts are popular and people are going back to their smaller devices. The point is, as an e-juice company with a goal of serving and satisfying every vaper, it is important to keep up with the times. Every flavor is like a work of art trapped in a bottle. What goes inside that bottle is based on customers wants and needs and is constantly evolving. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/flaving-stix-what-you-need-to-know</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T19:59:03-08:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T15:44:37-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/flaving-stix-what-you-need-to-know"/>
    <title>Flaving Stix: What You Need to Know!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Saabir Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong><u>What is a Disposable Vape?</u></strong></p>
<p><span>There is no denying that the vaping industry has been moving towards the trend of disposable vapes. So, what is this new and popular device? </span></p>
<p><span>A disposable vape is an e-cigarette that comes ready to vape and then is thrown away once the battery dies or the juice runs outs. The device comes in one piece consisting of a battery, atomizer, and a prefilled flavor cartridge. The battery activates once the user inhales from the mouthpiece, making this device one of the most simple and easy to use electronic cigarettes on the market today. </span></p>
<p><strong><u>Concerns Regarding the Use of Disposables Vapes</u></strong></p>
<p>The environment! Recent surveys showed that the number one reason consumers disapproved of disposable vapes is due to the amount of waste that they produce. Everything we buy comes in packaging. Our food, our electronics, toys, health products… the list goes on! Now on top of the packaging disposable vapes produce, they are also tossed way once they have run their course. This was an extremely important factor for us when developing our own disposable vape, and we have done the best we can to solve that with our Flaving Stix!</p>
<p><strong><u>VanGo Flaving Stix – Why they are different!</u></strong></p>
<p>VanGo Vapes is currently working on an all-in-one system that will bring to you all our top selling flavors in a simple disposable device. They are a 500 puff, 2.0 ml, British Columbia compliant disposable. The three <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs" title="Legendary">Legendary </a>flavors that will be included in the launch of this new system are <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-ophelia" title="Frozen Ophelia">Frozen Ophelia</a>, <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/the-root" title="The Root">The Root</a>, and the legendary <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/cactus-jango" title="Cactus Jango">Cactus Jango</a>! The nicotine used is a proprietary combination of different nicotine bases and we’ve decided to call it BoldSalts – because they make the hit in our Flaving Stix just so perfect! Here’s the kicker - alongside the launch of the Flaving Stix, VanGo Vapes will also be creating a recycling program that will allow consumers to recycle their used disposable vapes! This type of program is unique in our industry and is much needed when we consider how much waste consumer goods bring in general. As leaders of the vape industry here in Canada, we’re proud to be here to lead a change in how we deal with waste as a socially responsible organization!</p>
<p><strong><u>What to Remember</u></strong></p>
<p>It is important to remember that there is not much we do today that does not add to our carbon footprint. Our goal is to reduce it anyway that we can. Disposable vapes and their packaging will produce waste, but they will also help an entire population that is missing out on the benefits of vaping and Flaving. These devices bring a new age of nicotine delivery to the average consumer and for the first time, smoking is not more accessible than vaping. Tobacco smoke leads directly to the emission of 2,600,000 tons of carbon dioxide and about 5,200,000 tons of methane and that is simply not okay. With the launch of the VanGo Flaving Stix and the accompanied recycling program, our goal is to reduce number of smokers in the world while doing everything possible to reduce impacts on the environment!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-10-most-common-vaping-myths-debunked</id>
    <published>2020-11-16T20:57:01-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-16T21:02:30-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-10-most-common-vaping-myths-debunked"/>
    <title>The 10 Most Common Vaping Myths Debunked</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shawna Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<ol>
<li>
<span>Vaping is as harmful as smoking cigarettes</span>
<ul>
<li>
<span>FACT:</span> H<span>ardly anything is 100% safe, but studies show that e-cigarettes are substantially safer than traditional cigarettes. The nicotine in e-liquid is addictive but e-cigarettes do not produce tar or carbon monoxide which are just two of the most harmful elements produced from smoking cigarettes. <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/e-cigarettes-an-evidence-update">Public Health England</a> has conducted studies and from this have concluded that “E-cigarettes are 95% safer than smoked tobacco and they can help smokers quit. </span>
</li>
<li><span>There are around 250 harmful chemicals found in cigarettes.  At least 70 of them have been proven to cause cancer. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Vaping causes ‘Popcorn-lung’</span>
<ul>
<li><span>FACT: Popcorn – lung (Bronchiolitis Obliterans) is a serious but rare disease. Exposure to Diacetyl is the root cause. Popcorn lung was the term given to the lung condition that a small number of factory workers developed in a popcorn factory due to being exposed to elevated levels of this chemical. Diacetyl naturally occurs in chemicals produced in various fruits, vegetables and plants. The most notable of which is Tobacco. There is 750x more diacetyl in a pack of cigarettes than there is in one days’ worth of e-liquid, yet there is no found cases of popcorn lung in smokers.  It would take hundreds of days’ worth of vaping jam packed into one day to reach the same amounts of Diacetyl that is found in one pack of cigarettes. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Vaping is a gateway to smoking</span>
<ul>
<li><span>The opposite of this has been found. There is no evidence of people starting to vape and then switching to smoking, however multiple studies have concluded that people who have been smoking will make the switch to vaping.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Vaping is not regulated</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Multiple times a year new regulation is being put in place regarding vaping. As a somewhat newer industry, this is how things go. In Canada, the regulations are consistently being updated and access to the most up to date information continues to flow.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Vaping does not help you quit smoking</span>
<ul>
<li><span>This one is one of the craziest myths as there is plenty of evidence out there to suggest that using an e-cigarette has helped a lot of people in kicking the habit. Public Health England themselves have said that “an estimated 2.9 million adults in Great Britain currently use e-cigarettes and of these, 1.5 million people have completely stopped smoking.” E-cigarettes are now part of this year’s stop smoking campaign by PHE. We have been around for over 5 years, and pride ourselves on helping our customers to make the switch!</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>E cigs contain anti-freeze</span>
<ul>
<li><span>While it’s true that the e-liquid you’re using to vape may contain propylene glycol (an ingredient that can be found in anti-freeze), it is a substance that is recognized by internationally respected health organizations as being safe for human consumption. <br> What makes antifreeze toxic is an ingredient called ethylene glycol (a substance which should be noted is NOT found in e-liquid).</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>E cigarettes can be easily purchased by kids</span>
<ul>
<li><span>With all the different sweet e-liquid flavors available in the industry many people argue that this entices younger people to vape and then get into smoking. However, <a href="http://ash.org.uk/media-and-news/press-releases-media-and-news/new-research-by-ash-finds-use-of-electronic-cigarettes-remains-low-among-young-people/">repeated surveys</a> have shown only a negligible uptake among never-smokers, including young people. Smoking rates have also continued to decline amongst younger people and Public Health England are continually monitoring this. Furthermore, just like with tobacco, vape vendors also will challenge a purchaser’s age if they believe that they are under 18. Regulations have been set in place for stores to adhere to the restrictions of selling vape products to minors. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Secondhand vapor is as bad as secondhand smoke</span>
<ul>
<li><span>There is no doubt that it is just as possible to inhale secondhand vapor as it is to inhale secondhand smoke, however, there is no indication that vapor is a danger to those around you. Studies have failed to conclude that vaping liquid contains any of the toxins found in conventional cigarettes. There are no harmful elements in the vapor from e-cigarettes produced like there is in traditional cigarettes. Tests in non-ventilated vape shops have also been carried out and concluded that there was nothing from the vapor and in the air, that was dangerous to others.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span mce-data-marked="1">It is claimed that manufacturers hide product ingredients.</span><br>
<ul>
<li><span>Well this is just simply not true. As mass producers of the product, we can say with confidence that we know what we are putting in each bottle! For consumers, it is important to know your product and where it comes from. Just the way we would with any other product we purchase. The quality is knowledge based, just do your research! At Vango we use Vegetable Glycerin, Propylene glycol, food flavors, and nicotine.</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>e-Cigs are explosive</span>
<ul>
<li><span>The many headlines in the media about exploding e-cigs are almost universally related to improper use or storage of a battery. Carrying loose batteries in a pocket or bag is a big no, no. Just be sure to take care like you would with any other electrical items or lithium batteries and if you’re following the battery safety guidelines set by the manufacturer and use the device in the correct way this will not be an issue. You can view our <a href="https://startvaping.com/vaping-safety/">safety guidelines for vape batteries here.</a></span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-crew-the-vango-black-friday-special</id>
    <published>2020-11-16T20:24:54-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-16T20:38:28-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-crew-the-vango-black-friday-special"/>
    <title>The Crew: The VanGo Black Friday Special</title>
    <author>
      <name>Saabir Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered what the mint version of your vape would taste like? Or even vice versa and it's the non-mint version? Well wait no longer because if you're a fan of any of these "Crews" or pairs of juices, then you will not be disappointed.</p>
<p>We've got 3 Crews or Pairs that we've released over the years and each one of them deserves much more recognition. All of the menthols of course use our proprietary VanGo cooling blend, but you'll definitely find that each flavor has a different cooling variation. On top of that, when making menthol or non-menthol versions of flavors, it's never as simple as just adding mint or taking it out. Rather, we reformulate all the fruits and cooling from scratch to make each Flave a unique experience.</p>
<p>Now let's get into helping you choose YOUR Crew! Each crew contains<span> </span><strong>2 x FreeBase 30 mL bottles</strong><span> </span>and are all BC Compliant.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong><a title="Cactus Jango" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/cactus-jango" data-sanitized-data-mce-fragment="1" data-sanitized-data-mce-href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/cactus-jango">Cactus Jango</a><span> </span>&amp;<span> </span><a title="Jango Chill" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/jango-chill" data-sanitized-data-mce-fragment="1" data-sanitized-data-mce-href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/jango-chill">Jango Chill</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-ophelia" title="Frozen Ophelia">Frozen Ophelia</a><span> </span>&amp;<span> </span><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/galleria/products/ophelia" title="Ophelia">Ophelia</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/galleria/products/sophie" title="Sophie">Sophie<span> </span></a>&amp;<span> </span><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/frozen/products/frozen-sophene" title="Frozen Sophene">Frozen Sophene</a></strong></li>
</ol>
<p>First off we have<span> </span><a title="Cactus Jango" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/cactus-jango">Cactus Jango</a><span> </span>&amp;<span> </span><a title="Jango Chill" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/jango-chill">Jango Chill</a>. These two tropical flavors are composed of jackfruit, strawberry, cactus &amp; mango but<span> </span><a title="Jango Chill" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/jango-chill">Jango Chill</a><span> </span>is topped off with a bit of extra lychee and mint.</p>
<p>Next up we have the Ophelia's and between<span> </span><a title="Frozen Ophelia" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-ophelia">Frozen Ophelia</a><span> </span>and regular<span> </span><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/galleria/products/ophelia" title="Ophelia">Ophelia</a>, the key differences are the sweetener levels and the fact that<span> </span><a title="Frozen Ophelia" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/legendary-one-offs/products/frozen-ophelia">Frozen Ophelia</a><span> </span>is in fact, frozen and cold to the taste! Other than that, get a hold of this delicious cactus, mango, kiwi &amp; strawberry combination ASAP!</p>
<p>Finally there are the Soph's. These two flavors,<span> </span><a title="Sophie" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/galleria/products/sophie">Sophie<span> </span></a>and<span> </span><a title="Frozen Sophene" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/collections/frozen/products/frozen-sophene">Frozen Sophene</a><span> </span>are the newest to have been released, both coming out in 2020 and making waves in every market they hit. Comprised of pink guavas, pineapples and strawberries, you'll definitely be satisfied with either option!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/10-vaping-accessories-you-need</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T12:19:40-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T12:19:41-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/10-vaping-accessories-you-need"/>
    <title>10 Vaping Accessories You Need!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Saabir Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Regardless of the device you use, there are some everyday essentials that can make your vaping experience smooth and convenient! Here we have come up with the top 10 items our team at VanGo has deemed vital.</span></p>
<ol>
<li><strong><span>Carrying Case</span></strong></li>
</ol>
<p><span>There are often many knick-knacks that come with vaping and having one place to store everything so that they are always in arms reach can make your vaping experience far more efficient. When out and about, you can find everything you need in your day, tucked away safely in your carrying bag and ready if/when they are needed!</span></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/copy-of-efest-lush-v4-charger-4-bay?_pos=2&amp;_sid=1063ee357&amp;_ss=r" title="Efest Q4 Charger"><strong><span>Battery Charger</span></strong></a>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>This goes without saying. If you are using a device that requires your batteries to be recharged, having a durable battery charger is a must. You can keep one set charging while another set is in use to ensure you always have operating batteries.</span></p>
<p><span>If you're looking to pick one up, check out this <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/copy-of-efest-lush-v4-charger-4-bay?_pos=2&amp;_sid=1063ee357&amp;_ss=r" title="Efest Lush Q4 Charger 4 Bay">Efest Lush Q4 Charger that has 4 bays!</a></span></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Battery Pack</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>We have all been guilty of forgetting to charge our devices overnight and being incredibly frustrated when we head out the door with a vape that is not functioning. Having a pare battery pack to charge you up on the go is an awesome option!</span></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Cleaning Gear </span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Microfiber cloths, brushes, alcohol, and even a vape mat can help eliminate some of the mess! If not, it will help with the cleanup. These handy kits help store everything in one place for easy access!</span></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Coil Building Kit</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Coil building kits are great for people using a sub ohm device and even for some pod systems where changing the coil is necessary. They generally come with tweezers, flush cutters, coil rods, and scissors. You can also add an Ohm reader, pliers, screwdrivers and wire if you would like. These little kits are super handy and help keep you tools neat and organized.</span></p>
<ol start="6">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Tweezers</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Saabir Daya, Operations Manger at VanGo vapes says that, “tweezers are a small but extremely essential accessory for most vapors.” There are a couple different kinds but the most popular are <strong>ceramic tweezers</strong>, which are non-conductive which will allow you to strum your coils looking for hot spots, as well as <strong>needle-tip tweezers </strong>which can be used for placing your cotton. </span></p>
<ol start="7">
<li>
<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/kendo-cotton-gold-edition-now-20-more?_pos=1&amp;_sid=6d30b728a&amp;_ss=r" title="Kendo Cotton Gold"><strong><span>Cotton</span></strong></a>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Cotton is the middleman for your juice and your heating element. Choosing the right cotton is important. Kendo cotton is 100% organic, unbleached, heat resistant, odorless, low taste retention, easy to wick. It has superior absorption. 2X longer lasting and is Ready to Use. No Boiling Needed. </span></p>
<p>Check out the best cotton for any RDA or RDTA by clicking the link right over here: <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/kendo-cotton-gold-edition-now-20-more?_pos=1&amp;_sid=6d30b728a&amp;_ss=r" title="Kendo Cotton Gold Edition">Kendo Cotton Gold Edition!</a></p>
<ol start="8">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Vape bands</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<p><span>Vape bands are an excellent little addition to any vaporizer collection. They protect the glass on your tank, and you can make them fun with a variety of different colors and graphics!</span></p>
<ol start="9">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Spare parts</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>With all the items above, it is important to keep spares around. Spare coils, pods, screws, batteries etc. You can buy extra parts unique to each device.</span></p>
<ol start="10">
<li>
<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/frozen-menthol-ice-shot?_pos=1&amp;_psq=ice%20shot&amp;_ss=e&amp;_v=1.0" title="Ice Shot"><strong><span>VanGo Vapes’ Legendary Ice Shot</span></strong></a>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Last but certainly not least, an everyday essential for our entire team is the proprietary cooling agent, ICE SHOT. Add this to any juice to give it an icy kick. Sometimes menthol is not your all day but every now and then you might like a taste. That makes this little guy a fierce addition to your juice family!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/frozen-menthol-ice-shot?_pos=1&amp;_psq=ice%20shot&amp;_ss=e&amp;_v=1.0" title="Ice Shot"><span>Intrigued? Try some right over here!</span></a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vaping-terms-you-need-to-know</id>
    <published>2020-10-28T11:31:58-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-28T11:31:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vaping-terms-you-need-to-know"/>
    <title>Vaping Terms You Need to Know!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shawna Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Have you ever wanted to change something in your life, but the fear of not knowing where to start stopped you? A new diet, a hobby, or quitting a bad habit? There is always a fountain of knowledge waiting to be soaked in, and that can be intimidating! If you are thinking about quitting smoking and want to make the switch to vaping, continue reading below for the basic terms you need to know. Let us tackle this fear together! </span></p>
<p><strong><span>The first step is picking out your device. Below are some options:</span></strong></p>
<p><strong><span>Electronic Cigarettes</span></strong><span> – This is a simple place to start. You open them and they are ready to go! Once you are finished with them, you may even dispose of them and get another one. These devices work great with higher nicotine strengths and give a satisfying hit. They are suitable place to start if you are making the switch from smoking and need somewhere to start from.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Pods</span></strong><span> – Generally a two-piece device, this system proves to be a practical option. They are small like an e-cigarette but have replaceable or refillable pods. It pairs great with NicSalts and is often a more affordable option as well.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Box Mods</span></strong><span> – These are larger and usually more powerful vapes. They have external batteries that you recharge. Box mods are generally for the more experienced vapor but with the right information they are simple to learn! There are more setting and features such as wattage control and temperature control</span></p>
<p><em><span>After picking a device, you now need to decide on whether you want to vape a freebase e-liquid or one based in NicSalts.</span></em></p>
<p><strong><span>Freebase - </span></strong><span>Freebase is the traditional base in e-liquids, which also means that the nicotine is purer in a sense. They have a different proportion of PG/VG with 70% VG and 30% PG in most liquids to keep it thick enough for sub ohm devices. The nicotine levels for freebase e-liquids come at 0, 3, 6, 12 &amp; 18 mg per mL. Free base pairs well with the box mod devices or more powerful vapes in general.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>NicSalts </span></strong><span>– Most NicSalt e-juices tend to be 50/50 when it comes to the ratio of VG and PG. This makes the e-liquid slightly thinner, making it easier for smaller devices to handle and creates a cleaner hit for mouth to lung vaping. Salts generally come in 10, 20, 35 &amp; 50 mg per mL. Salts pair well with the pod systems and anything that fires at lower power settings.</span></p>
<p><em><span>Once you are ready with your knowledge on how to vape, picking the flavor is the fun part and totally discretionary as well!</span></em> 😊</p>
<p><strong><span>Check out <a href="http://www.vangovapes.com">www.vangovapes.com</a> for our wide variety of flavors! </span></strong></p>
<p><span>Below are some terms that may make your experience with vaping even smoother:</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Atomizer </span></strong><span>– This is the heating element inside of your e-cigarette device. As the coil inside heats up, the liquid begins to evaporate, producing vapor.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Cartomizer</span></strong><span> – A cartridge with a built-in atomizer. There is no need to change coils or update your atomizer. When you change your capsule, your atomizer starts fresh too.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Cartridge</span></strong><span> - The removable container that holds the pre-filled e-liquid and often has a clean and easy integrated coil system.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Coil</span></strong><span> - The metal heat-conductor within the heating element.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Resistance - </span></strong><span>The rate at which electricity can travel through the heating element. A lower resistance provides faster heating and greater vapor, while high resistance results in slower heating with less produced vapor.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Wattage</span></strong><span> – This is essentially the output or power of a device. A mod set at 50W will vaporize more e-liquid than a mod at 30W, just as a 75W light bulb will be brighter than a 40W bulb</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Wick</span></strong><span> - The absorbent material that draws e-liquid up into the heating element to be turned into vapor.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/citrus-bonanza-the-ultimate-citrus-flaves</id>
    <published>2020-10-27T18:09:55-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-27T18:14:33-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/citrus-bonanza-the-ultimate-citrus-flaves"/>
    <title>Citrus Bonanza - The Ultimate Citrus Flaves!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Saabir Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When life gives you lemons, make some mouth-watering e-liquid!!!<br>Have you tried VanGo Vapes citrus flavors before? Let me tell you, they are a bottle full of bliss!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/pre-sale-shivers-citrus-jive?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ceb78f588&amp;_ss=r" title="Citrus Jive">Citrus Jive</a> from the Shivers line up is a perfectly sweet and tart combination of lemons and lime bursting with juicy tangerines and freshly squeezed oranges, slightly cooled to the perfect level!</p>
<p>Are you drooling yet? Wait - there's more! <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/sweet-citrus?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ec645d72b&amp;_ss=r" title="Sweet Citrus">Sweet Citrus</a> is a blast of Orange and Tangerine with hints of Lemon and Lime. Released in mid 2019, it quickly raced up our leaderboard to become one of our most popular flavors!</p>
<p> <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/pre-sale-shivers-citrus-jive?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ceb78f588&amp;_ss=r" title="Citrus Jive"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/VGV_Profile_CitrusJive_V2_240x240.png?v=1603847157" alt="Citrus Jive"></a><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/sweet-citrus?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ec645d72b&amp;_ss=r" title="Sweet Citrus"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/VGV_Profile_SweetCitrus_V2_240x240.png?v=1603847142" alt="Sweet Citrus"></a></p>
<p>When asked about why the VanGo Vapes CEO chose to focus on citrus, Saadiq Daya said, “my palette has always enjoyed citrus, so I knew I wanted to create a flavor that could ignite that same explosion of flavors. I couldn’t pick between the two because they both were exactly what I was looking for in their own ways, so we dropped them at the same time!”</p>
<p>The biggest differences in these two is that the <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/pre-sale-shivers-citrus-jive?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ceb78f588&amp;_ss=r" title="Citrus Jive">Citrus Jive</a> has a light version of the VanGo proprietary cooling blend. Both took roughly 1 year to create and perfect and then were showcased side by side at CVE Edmonton 2019. If you have yet to try them, we encourage you to join the party! 😊</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/pre-sale-shivers-citrus-jive?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ceb78f588&amp;_ss=r" title="Try Citrus Jive">Try Citrus Jive Here!</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/sweet-citrus?_pos=1&amp;_sid=ec645d72b&amp;_ss=r" title="Sweet Citrus">Click Here for Sweet Citrus.</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-consequences-of-the-master-settlement-agreement</id>
    <published>2020-10-27T17:19:30-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-27T17:21:09-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-consequences-of-the-master-settlement-agreement"/>
    <title>The Master Settlement Agreement</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shawna Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>How do we silence the voices of those suffering at the hands of big tobacco? Well we pay them of course! This is what the MSA (Tobacco Master Settlement Agreement) sought to do in November of 1998. The Master Settlement Agreement is an accord reached between the state Attorneys General of 46 states, five U.S. territories, the District of Columbia and the four largest cigarette manufacturers in America concerning the advertising, marketing and promotion of cigarettes.</p>
<p>This agreement stated that tobacco companies would make life-long payments to state governments to cover the cost of smoking-related illnesses. The minimum amount to be paid over the first 25 years was to be $206 billion. The endless amounts of research indicating that cigarettes were linked to a rise in lung cancer and other health issues was on the rise and people were starting to come forward. Over 800 private claims were made against tobacco companies suing them for negligence, causing health problems. Of these 800 claims, Big Tobacco won EVERY SINGLE ONE! These companies pleaded ignorance, stating they did not know the harms of cigarettes.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/EGKsYoIXYAAB-iN.jpg?v=1603844104" alt="">The question is, if you can win every private lawsuit, why pay billions of dollars in reparations to the state governments? There was obviously harm done, and they knew it and needed to cover their tracks. With the rise of smoking, more people started getting sick which meant higher state medical costs. The amount each state receives is based on tobacco sales. The higher the tobacco sales the higher the payout. That is insane! What a loophole they found. By paying the billions of dollars settled upon in the MSA, big tobacco is essentially bulletproof. They did this to be free from any burden of class actions lawsuits. So, big tobacco continues to make the big bucks, essentially profiting of health issues of everyday people which they no longer hold liability for, only having to increase payments in states which they sell the most tobacco products. This is simply a marketing strategy not a settlement for harm done.</p>
<p>With the billions allocated to these states, only a small percentage is spent on smoking cessation programs and tobacco prevention! In fact, in 2018 less than 3% of the 27.5 billion was spent on such things. If the harms of tobacco are known and prevention is key, this is where the spending should be. The reality is it is not, and that is something to really think about.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/coils-everything-you-need-to-know</id>
    <published>2020-09-15T11:33:59-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-15T11:35:05-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/coils-everything-you-need-to-know"/>
    <title>Coils: Everything You Need to Know!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shawna Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>There are a wide variety of different coils in the market, and this can be overwhelming to the new or even experienced vaper. Knowledge of each type and how they work can be key to a great vaping experience! The coil is crucial to the vaping process, so let us start with the basics of what coils are.</span></p>
<p><span>The coil is often referred to as the heart of the atomizer. They are made of resistive wire and absorbent material. The coil is the unit responsible for heating up the e-liquid and creating the vapor. The resistance of the coil can be modified by adjusting the number of wraps of wire there are. The most common materials coils are made of include kanthal, nichrome, titanium, stainless steel, and nickel. However, the most common of these is kanthal.  The resistance of kanthal is stable across different wattages making it an excellent choice for any vaping device on the market. </span></p>
<p><span>After exploring the different materials, an understanding of wire gauges comes next. This is a measurement of how thick the wire is. Thicker wire has less resistance and slower ramp up time, thinner wire has higher resistance and quicker ramp up time. What you choose will be based on the type of vape experience you are going for!</span></p>
<p><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/Background.png?v=1600194547" alt="Wire Gauges: From Thinnest to Thickest" width="" height=""></span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p><span>Now that we have looked at wire materials and the different gauges and their use, lets look at the different types of coils. </span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<span>Standard coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Kanthal wire</span></li>
<li><span>Horizontally orientated</span></li>
<li><span>Wraps that do not touch</span></li>
<li><span>Wick inserted through center</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Vertical coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Kanthal wire</span></li>
<li><span>Vertically orientated </span></li>
<li><span>Wick wrapped around the outside</span></li>
<li><span>Offer great wicking and improved airflow</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Dual/triple/quadruple coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Numerous coils in one setup</span></li>
<li><span>Reduces resistance </span></li>
<li><span>Reduces ramp-up time </span></li>
<li><span>Higher wattages</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Parallel coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Dual coils</span></li>
<li><span>Two strands wrapped together not separate </span></li>
<li><span>One wick can be used for easier setup</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Clapton coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Like a standard coil but uses Clapton wire</span></li>
<li><span>Thicker center with thinner wire wrapped around</span></li>
<li><span>Greater surface area</span></li>
<li><span>Increases vapor produced</span></li>
<li><span>Longer ramp-up time</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Twisted coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Like a standard coil but more complicated wire</span></li>
<li><span>Wires twisted together to get two strands in one</span></li>
<li><span>Improves vapor produced </span></li>
<li><span>Improves flavor</span></li>
<li><span>Longer ramp-up time</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span>Tiger coils</span>
<ul>
<li><span>Like Clapton but outer layer uses kanthal ribbon</span></li>
<li><span>Boosts surface area</span></li>
<li><span>Improved vapor produced </span></li>
<li><span>Improved flavor</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span>Deciding on which coil is best for you starts with an understanding of how each one works. Most vapers use sub ohm tanks with pre-made coils. These coils usually use kanthal wire and a standard design! As discussed above, the material, resistance and wattage are what will give the unique vaping experience you are looking for. Lower resistance coils heat up quicker and produce more vapor. The higher resistance coils are better for “mouth-to lung” and tend to be preferred by smokers who have recently switched to vaping. Making sure the coil you choose is compatible with your tank is also important. </span></p>
<p><span>The following blog dove into the basic understanding of coils, however, the best way to ensure you have found the right fit is to speak with someone experienced in the vaping industry. Our goal at VanGo is to make sure our customers continue to have all their vaping needs met and all their questions answered! Someone on the team is always ready to lend advice! </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/federal-vaping-regulations-what-you-need-to-know</id>
    <published>2020-08-20T09:17:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-15T11:36:32-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/federal-vaping-regulations-what-you-need-to-know"/>
    <title>The 2020 Federal Vaping Regulation Update</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>As of July 1st, 2020 the TVPA (Tobacco and Vaping Products Act) issued new federal regulations on advertising and labeling for all vape related products. (<a href="http://gazette.gc.ca/rp-pr/p2/2020/2020-07-08/html/sor-dors143-eng.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CLICK HERE FOR MORE</a>) It is now prohibited to advertise vaping products in public spaces if the ads can be seen or heard by youth. This includes commercials, media, street signs, and products must not be visible through store windows.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><br>All e-liquid and vaping related products must also include a single health warning outlined by the List of Health Warnings for Vaping Product Advertising. The word warning must be upper-cased and bold and the be inside a rectangular box with a black or white background. An example of what you will see now is “WARNING: Vaping products contain nicotine, a highly addictive chemical.” See the image below for a before and after compliance label.<br><br><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/2020_06_15_Banner_Instagram_NewLabels_001f9862-0cac-478e-92f5-e434e79eec52_large.jpg?v=1597940381" style="float: none;"><br><br>Beyond federal regulations, are the individual provincial regulations. Below we will break some of those down for you in order to shed light on what is to come in the next few weeks.</p>
<p><br><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>British Columbia</strong> </span></em></p>
<ul>
<li>all E-substances that do not contain nicotine, and those that contain both nicotine and cannabis, will be prohibited for sale.</li>
<li>Cannabis-only vapor products continue to be available for sale through authorized cannabis retailers.</li>
<li>Retailers cannot sell any E-substances that contain only flavored chemicals (i.e. substances that do not contain nicotine, or nicotine salts or cannabis).</li>
<li>All advertising of vapor products that can be seen, accessed, or heard by youth is prohibited. This includes places such as store windows and transit hubs.</li>
<li>New business owners must notify the Ministry of Health of their intention to sell restricted E-substances at least 6 weeks prior to their first sale by using the (NOI) form.</li>
<li>New business owners must report the products they wish to sell to the Ministry of Health at least 6 weeks prior to their first sale by submitting a product report, and a manufacturing report.</li>
<li>Current vaping tax is 20% plus the 7% HST.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Alberta</strong></em></span><br>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bill 19</strong></li>
<ul>
<li>Prohibits the sale, possession and use of vapour products by anyone under 18, which aligns with the province’s age of majority.</li>
<li>Prohibits the use of vapour product in schools, hospitals, and other public spaces.</li>
<li>Prohibits advertising in gas stations and convenience stores, to align with tobacco advertising regulations and federal vapour product regulations.</li>
<li>Restricts where vapour products can be sold.</li>
<li>Establishes the authority to consider flavour restrictions at a later date.</li>
</ul>
<li>As of right now, Alberta is to comply with the federal regulations, but no new provincial regulations have been sealed.</li>
<li>Alberta is also looking at the introduction of a 20%tax.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Saskatchewan</strong></em></span></p>
<ul>
<li>No sale to minors under the age of 18.</li>
<li>Prohibits promotion of products in businesses frequented by youth.</li>
<li>Prohibited to vape in public buildings, schools and school grounds.</li>
</ul>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Manitoba</strong></span></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Minimum age of 18.</li>
<li>Ban on vaping in indoor public places like schools, libraries, hospitals, malls, restaurants, indoor workplaces.</li>
<li>The province’s regulations on advertising and promotion of tobacco products now includes vaping products as well.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Ontario</strong> </em></span></p>
<ul>
<li>The sale of flavored vapor products will be restricted to specialty vape stores and licensed cannabis retail stores. Convenience stores can only sell tobacco, menthol and mint flavored vapor products;</li>
<li>The sale of vapor products with high nicotine concentrations (greater than 20 mg/ml) will be restricted to specialty vape stores.</li>
<li>Specialty vape stores will no longer be permitted to have indoor displays and promotions that are visible from outside their stores.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Quebec</strong></em></span></p>
According to<strong> Bill 44</strong>, it’s forbidden to:<br>
<ul>
<li> Allow e-cigarettes and related accessories to be seen from the outside of a shop. To prevent this, you’ll need to frost your window.</li>
<li>Communicate to consumers inappropriately regarding tobacco products displayed in the shop. This means a seller cannot communicate on the alleged benefits of vaping.</li>
<li>Advertise a vaping product whose sale or distribution is forbidden. In broad terms, ad in newspapers, posters, leaflets, Facebook posts, or on any other social network are not allowed. Likewise, it is not possible for a vape seller in Quebec to own a website that promotes its products.</li>
<li>Allow clients to test products or flavours. If you run a vape shop, you can’t allow a potential client test any products nor demonstrate how they work. Both owners and clients complain about this but it’s the law.</li>
<li> Sell, or offer products other than those related to e-cigarettes. For instance, owners or shop staff cannot offer food or water to clients, neither for free or at a price.</li>
<li>Offer loyalty cards or any discounts or coupons.</li>
<li>Sell vaping products, to minors, nor allow their presence within the shop. The client or visitor must prove he is over the age of legal majority. If the seller doubts the age of a visitor, he must ask for ID.</li>
<li>Fail to display, in full view of everyone, on the cash registers or near them, messaging regarding the ban on the sale of tobacco to minors and the health warnings from the Ministère de la Santé et des Services sociaux.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>New Brunswick</strong></em></span></p>
<ul>
<li>No sale to minors under the age of 19.</li>
<li>Cannot enter the store unless accompanied by an adult.</li>
<li>Outdoor advertising by vape shops is prohibited and promotional material inside the shops cannot be viewed from the outside.</li>
<li>The sale of flavoured tobacco, including menthol, is also banned</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Nova Scotia</strong> </em></span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;"><strong>FULL flavor ban.</strong></span></li>
<li>20mg maximum nicotine strength.</li>
<li>Tax Rates on Vaping Products.</li>
<li>Effective September 15, 2020 every consumer shall pay tax at the rate of:</li>
<li>For vaping substance that is a liquid $0.50 per millilitre;</li>
<li>For vaping substance that is a solid $0.50 per gram;</li>
<li>For vaping devices other than vaping packages 20% of the manufacturer’s or importer’s suggested retail selling price;</li>
<li>For vaping packages, the greater of 20% of the manufacturer’s or importer’s suggested retail selling price, and $0.50 per millilitre or gram of the included vaping substance;</li>
<li>On top of HST.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>PEI</strong></em></span><br>
<ul>
<li>Raised the legal age to buy vape products from 19 to 21.</li>
<li>Ban on certain flavors.</li>
<li>Sales banned wherever tobacco sales are prohibited.</li>
<li>No advertising at vape shops in a way that is visible from the outside.</li>
</ul>
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Newfoundland</strong></em></span><br>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>No sales to minors under the age of 19.</li>
<li>Sales banned wherever tobacco products are prohibited.</li>
<li>No advertising where it is visible from the outside.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Yukon</strong></em></span></p>
<ul>
<li>The minimum legal age for purchasing tobacco and vaping products is now 19.</li>
<li>Providing or selling vaping products and tobacco to minors under the age of 19 is illegal.</li>
<li>New signage requirements mean that “no vaping” as well as “no smoking” signs should be posted.</li>
<li>Vaping and tobacco products are now regulated the same way:</li>
<ul>
<li>location of sales; </li>
<li>consumption in public places; and</li>
<li>restrictions on product promotion.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Northwest Territories</strong></span></em></p>
<ul>
<li>No sale to minors under the age of 19.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Nunavut</strong></em></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Current regulations only dictate where people can vape.</li>
</ul>
<p>Many of these provincial regulations have been in place for some time, and there still may be changes to come. However, this is the most up to date information on a breakdown of each province. VanGo Vapes will continue to persevere through these updated regulations and to meet all compliance so we can continue to serve our great vape community!<br><br></p>
<p><em><strong>Stay<span> </span>tuned for the next blog posts!</strong></em></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/in-the-now-bc-2020-vaping-regulations-everything-you-need-to-know</id>
    <published>2020-08-13T11:43:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-13T11:50:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/in-the-now-bc-2020-vaping-regulations-everything-you-need-to-know"/>
    <title>Everything About BC Vaping Regulations</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>      September 15th 2020, a tidal wave of new vaping regulations is about to hit the province of British Columbia. At VanGo vapes we are committed to the well-being of both our wholesale and our retail customers and we understand that knowledge is power. This blog strives to give you all the information you need to know about what is coming and how you can prepare.</p>
<p><br><span>      </span>The ESR is B.C.’s new E-Substance Regulation. The Ministry of health announced in July of 2020 that EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY:</p>
<ul>
<li>All E-substances that do not contain nicotine, and those that contain both nicotine and cannabis, will be prohibited for sale.</li>
<li>Cannabis-only vapor products continue to be available for sale through authorized cannabis retailers.</li>
<li>Retailers cannot sell any E-substances that contain only flavored chemicals (i.e. substances that do not contain nicotine, or nicotine salts or cannabis).</li>
<li>All advertising of vapor products that can be seen, accessed, or heard by youth is prohibited. This includes places such as store windows and transit hubs.</li>
<li>New business owners must notify the Ministry of Health of their intention to sell restricted E-substances at least 6 weeks prior to their first sale by using the (NOI) form.</li>
<li>New business owners must report the products they wish to sell to the Ministry of Health at least 6 weeks prior to their first sale by submitting a product report, and a manufacturing report.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Effective after September 15th 2020</strong></em></span></p>
<ol>
<li>All flavored restricted E-substances – except tobacco flavor- can only be sold at age-restricted sales premises.</li>
<li>Retailers selling restricted E-substances must ensure that the E-substances they sell meet the requirements with respect to labelling, packaging volume, concentration and flavor.</li>
<li>All retailers must comply with the notification and reporting requirements under the ESR. (<a href="https://www2.gov.bc.ca/assets/gov/health/keeping-bc-healthy-safe/tobacco-regulation/bcs_esubstancereg_guide.pdf" target="_blank" title="CLICK HERE FOR MORE INFO" rel="noopener noreferrer">CLICK HERE FOR MORE</a>)</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>So what does all this mean? Let us break it down!</strong></em></span></p>
<p><strong>Sales premises</strong> – There are two different types of sales premises in which vapor products may be sold. These include age-restricted premises as well as all-age premises. There are new requirements for the types of products that each retailer type can sell. Age-restricted premises (those under the age of 19 cannot enter), such as specialized vapor product stores, tobacco flavored E-substances and other flavored restricted E-substances may be sold, However, no retailer may sell the flavors listed in Schedule 3 of the federal Tobacco and Vapor Products Act (<a href="https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/t-11.5/FullText.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CLICK HERE FOR MORE</a>). All-age premises (where persons under the age of 19 can enter) such as convenience stores, gas stations and other retail establishments, only restricted E-substances that taste or smell of tobacco may be sold. No other flavors are allowed.</p>
<p><br><strong>Packaging –</strong> Retailers are only permitted to sell restricted E-substances in plain packages without images and which include the following information.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nicotine strength</li>
<li>Total volume of E-substance per package or per cartridge if the package contains multiple containers or cartridges</li>
<li>“WARNING; nicotine is highly addictive” along with the symbol. What can be included is the contact information of the manufacturer, the brand and product name and the type of product (i.e. pod, pre-filled vape pen, e-liquid).</li>
</ul>
<strong>Volume and Concentration</strong> – Retailers <strong>cannot</strong> sell any E-substance that contains a nicotine concentration of more that 20mg/ml. Any refillable container that can hold more than 30mls, or any tank/cartridge that holds or can hold more than 2 mls.
<p> </p>
<p><br><strong>Notifications and Reporting – Notice of Intent</strong><br>Before selling any E-substance, business owners must notify the Ministry of Health. The NOI forms can be found online. (<a href="https://www2.gov.bc.ca/gov/content/health/keeping-bc-healthy-safe/tobacco-vapour/notice-of-intent-vapour-products">CLICK HERE FOR MORE</a>) The information to be included is;</p>
<ul>
<li>Legal name of business</li>
<li>Name under which business is conducted</li>
<li>Address of sales premises from which restricted e-substance is sold</li>
<li>Phone number for sales premises</li>
<li>Email address for sales premises</li>
<li>Webpage for sales premises</li>
<li>Whether or not persons under 19 are permitted on premises</li>
<li>Health authority in which the sales premises is located</li>
</ul>
<p>Submission of the NOI must be done 6 weeks before the retailer intends to sell restricted e-substances. <strong>However</strong>, there is a transition period for retailers who began selling these substances prior to the ESR. These retailers need to submit their NOI 6 weeks before September 15th, 2020. After the first submission, business owners must submit a NOI annually before January 15th of each year.</p>
<p><em><strong>Product report</strong></em><br> Along with the NOI, a product report needs to be submitted. This report must include;</p>
<ul>
<li>The name and contact information of the manufacturer</li>
<li>The brand name and product name</li>
<li>The type of product</li>
<li>The concentration of nicotine</li>
<li>The capacity (in ml) of either the refillable container or the tank/cartridge to hold the substance</li>
<li>The list of all ingredients (both common and scientific names) where applicable</li>
</ul>
<p>If any changes are to be made to any of the items listed above, business owners have 7 days to report it to the Ministry of Health.</p>
<p><br><em><strong>Manufacture report</strong></em><br>Manufacture reports must be submitted 6 weeks before the retailer first sells the product. Business owners must report the name and contact information of the manufacturer for each ingredient they use, along with each ingredients common and scientific names (if both names are available).</p>
<p><em><strong>Sales report</strong></em><br>Business owners must report their vapor product sales annually. For each type of vapor product sold, business owners must report:</p>
<ul>
<li>The number of containers and cartridges sold, grouped by name and product name</li>
<li>The volume (in mls) of restricted e-substance in the product</li>
<li>The flavor, if the restricted e-substance in the product is flavored</li>
</ul>
<p>This information must be collected from the period of October 1 -September 30 of the following year and submitted before January 15th of every year. These reports can be emailed to <a href="mailto:vaping.info@gov.bc.ca">vaping.info@gov.bc.ca</a></p>
<p><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Our promise to our valued customers!</strong></em></span><br>We are all in this together. The vaping industry is a thriving but very volatile industry with changes constantly being thrown at us. At VanGo vapes we pride ourselves on staying up to date with all the latest information and delivering it to you guys so we can all feel comfortable moving forward. We are currently “under-construction” and taking all the steps necessary to comply with the ESR. The line of communication will always be open for any question’s you guys may have, and we will work together to get through these coming weeks! <br><br>Links for more information: <br>E-Substance Guide - https://www2.gov.bc.ca/assets/gov/health/keeping-bc-healthy-safe/tobacco-regulation/bcs_esubstancereg_guide.pdf<br>Full Law Coverage - https://laws-lois.justice.gc.ca/eng/acts/t-11.5/FullText.html<br>Notice of Intent Vapour Products - https://www2.gov.bc.ca/gov/content/health/keeping-bc-healthy-safe/tobacco-vapour/notice-of-intent-vapour-products</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/bcs-new-vaping-regulations</id>
    <published>2020-07-23T18:01:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-23T18:32:35-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/bcs-new-vaping-regulations"/>
    <title>BC&apos;s New Vaping Regulations</title>
    <author>
      <name>Saabir Daya</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div><strong>New British Columbia Vaping Regulations Announced &amp; Effective September 2020</strong></div>
<br>
<div><strong></strong></div>
<p>There are some big changes coming around for all retailers in BC with the recently announced provincial vaping regulations. On top of the previously passed vaping tax, we now have the following to prepare for as it will be enforced starting September 1, 2020.</p>
<br>
<ol>
<li><strong>Flavored e-Juices are restricted to vape shops only.</strong></li>
<li><strong>All e-Juice bottles can not exceed a 30 mL Size.</strong></li>
<li><strong>No e-Juice may contain more than 20 mg of Nicotine.</strong></li>
<li><strong>All vaporizer tanks must have a capacity of less than 2 mL.</strong></li>
<li><strong>All e-Juice labels will have plain packaging - no pictures.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Non-nicotine e-juice is considered a health hazard and is banned.</strong></li>
<li><strong>No advertising of vaping products where a minor can view or hear it.</strong></li>
<li>
<strong>If you plan on retailing vape products, a letter of intent must be filed annually. On top of that, annual sales reports from Oct 1 to Sept 30 are required for filing as well.</strong> </li>
</ol>
<br>
<div>The regulations are an interesting take on the vaping industry. While it is clear that the government agrees that vaping plays an important role in the transition from smoking to vaping, we don't feel that they are being fair to the industry that is focusing on the adult vaping market.</div>
<div></div>
<br>
<div></div>
<div>Regulations like plain packaging not only destroy the creativity in this industry, but are also way above the regulations set out by Federal government. If the products are being sold in age restricted environments, it is unnecessary to have plain packaging; following the federal requirements should be sufficient. They have been clear about removing child appealing elements, cartoons, figures, pictures of restricted flavors like candy, confectionery, etc.</div>
<div></div>
<br>
<div>Restricting flavors to vape stores only is a smart move, and it helps control the vaping market. It ensures that adults trying to quit smoking will be directed to the proper channels to get the assistance they need, and will stop big tobacco from rolling out a bunch of flavors to its supply chain.</div>
<div></div>
<br>
<div>Restricting the nicotine content to 20 mg should be a regulation similar to the flavor one; vape shops should be able to carry higher nicotine amounts, up to the amount allowed federally (66 mg). 50 mg is a very effective tool for helping smokers quit, especially when they are using a small device that doesn't vaporize a lot at one time. A person coming from 2 packs a day either needs 50 mg of nicotine, or a stronger device with the 20 mg liquid. In regards to 0 mg liquid, there is no reason that it should fall under the same legislation, as it is literally food flavors, diluted with VG. It contains no nicotine; no addictive chemical.</div>
<div></div>
<br>
<div>The 30 ml bottle cap is another restriction that I feel is unnecessary, and without enough logic. Not only is it going to push people online, but it will require retailers to dispose of a lot of stock that will become illegal very soon, as well, will require people to use more packaging. Someone that is used to buying 60 or 120 ml will now have to buy many bottles to have the same amount.</div>
<div></div>
<br>
<div>Overall I believe that the government is starting to go in the right direction, compared to the proposed regs set out in January, however, there needs to be some amendments to meet the industry in the middle ground, and to ensure that adult smokers trying to quit are able to get what they need.</div>
<div></div>
<br>
<div>We are waiting on more updates and some clarification in regards to the exact rules on the packaging, sales, and reporting, will keep you all posted as we get the news.</div>
<br><style></style><style></style><style></style><style></style>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/does-vaping-increase-the-chance-of-covid-19</id>
    <published>2020-03-08T09:56:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-19T10:07:12-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/does-vaping-increase-the-chance-of-covid-19"/>
    <title>Does vaping increase the chance of COVID 19?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>On Sunday, New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio wildly <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/video/nyc-mayor-bill-de-blasio-coronavirus-update-today-2020-03-08/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">claimed</a> that vaping makes the risk of getting the feared Corona Virus COVID 19 higher. This claim of his was based on the wildly ridiculous “proof” that a 22-year-old man has the illness and is a vaper…</p>
<p><br>Not that there is any higher prevalence of the sickness or anything, but that there is one case. This is like saying that people who drive Toyota’s have a higher chance of getting the coronavirus because there is an ill person who drives a Toyota. As is the case with many news articles, in the article that wrote about this by CBS, the truth is hidden near the end where it states that “most experts acknowledge that it's still too early to know for sure" and that any connection is just a "possibility."</p>
<p><br>Vaping is said to be <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2018/dec/28/vaping-is-95-safer-than-smoking-claims-public-health-england" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">95% healthier</a> than cigarette smoking according to health experts, and so even if there is a correlation drawn that people that smoke cigarettes have a higher chance of getting the disease (a correlation between smoking and susceptibility towards the coronavirus), you cannot assume that it carries over to vapers. Until now the only valid negative statement that health officials can say about vaping is that it the long-term effects are not known, but if the alternative is cigarettes than what is the issue?</p>
<p><br>Of course, the issue is money. Pharmaceutical companies and tobacco companies the like feel threatened by the success rates vaping has on people trying to quit vaping, and so their pawns like Bill de Blasio feel the need to prop them up a notch.</p>
<p><br>With the seriousness of COVID 19 getting dire, now is the time where the media should be focusing on educating the people with the truth, facts and how to stay safe. Attacks on something so irrelevant to the disease like vaping only serves to confuse and hurt people, and will make this scary issue even worse.</p>
<p><em><strong>Stay<span> </span>tuned for the next blog posts!</strong></em></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-fight-for-nova-scotia</id>
    <published>2020-03-05T10:20:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-19T10:28:17-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-fight-for-nova-scotia"/>
    <title>The Fight for Nova Scotia</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>After last fall’s surprise announcement by the government of Nova Scotia to ban flavoured eliquids by April 1, 2020, they finally started listening to the public. It “only” took the CVA (Canadian Vaping Association’s) postcard backed campaign where over 1,400 cards were mailed to the Department of Health as well as 4,000 signatures from vape shops in Nova Scotia.</p>
<p><br>Unfortunately, this is after another ridiculous and irresponsible rule they announced regarding taxes; a $0.50 tax per MILLILITER. This means that high nicotine devices backed by tobacco companies like JUUL will have only around $1.50 per box of cartridge. It also means that low nicotine solutions like ones produced by many small Canadian producers will be priced out. A 60ml bottle that goes for an average of $30 will be double the price at $60.</p>
<p><br>This unfair and ridiculous move will force many vapers to go back to smoking, which is confirmed by even <a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/services/smoking-tobacco/vaping/smokers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Health Canada</a> to be “less harmful than smoking”. This is where we are at now. On Thursday March 5th, 2020, not even one month from when the rules are to take place, the Nova Scotia Legislature’s law amendments committee is hearing from the public. The public overwhelmingly is against this rule, pleading with the government that enacting these laws will “unfairly affect small businesses and adult consumers”, as narrated by the <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/vaping-smoking-e-cigarettes-health-care-1.5487385" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CBC.</a></p>
<p><br>Jody Allen who is the owner of the Vapour Trail chain of vape stores correctly stated that “"If big tobacco designed a vaping control policy framework to advantage themselves, they could not have done better than what Nova Scotia has done," These laws only help the companies that have been profiting off death for decades, and unless the Liberal MLA’s of Nova Scotia changes these rules they will be looked at by history as a government that put unreasonable rhetoric and propaganda ahead of the lives of their constituents.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/effects-of-vaping-propaganda-in-the-uk</id>
    <published>2020-03-01T10:21:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-19T10:26:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/effects-of-vaping-propaganda-in-the-uk"/>
    <title>Effects of Vaping Propaganda in the UK</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>According to an <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/false-fears-preventing-smokers-from-using-e-cigarettes-to-quit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">independent report</a> commissioned by Public Health England, smokers in the UK incorrectly believe that vapes are equally or more harmful than smoking. This is despite the UK governments continuous education and studies showing the opposite.</p>
<p><br>A huge cause of this is the CDC and their framing of the health problem that happened in the US last year. The deaths from “EVALI” were caused by vaping on vitamin E acetate, which is both illegal in the UK as well as not something that is used in nicotine vaping products anywhere. This substance is a thickening agent usually added to cannabis to dilute the solution in order to save money. What this has caused is countless more smokers to keep smoking and thereby killing themselves. While experts have consistently concluded that using vaping devices are far less harmful than smoking, it raises huge question on why people are refusing to believe the experts?</p>
<p><br>Confirmation bias is one reason. Smokers see vaping as a change and a challenge that rocks their own view of themselves and the world around them. In the backs of their mind, vaping represents a choice that they don’t want to make but should make because of their health and is the rational switch. However that option also means that every day they don’t make the switch they are being irrational and just wrong.</p>
<p><br>They want to believe that this is not the case; that they are stuck smoking because there are no better ways of nicotine intake without the negative side effects of smoking cigarettes. These people ignore the truth and latch onto the fake news stories sensationalizing the tragedies that something unrelated to vaping nicotine caused because it’s the easy way to sleep at night.</p>
<p><br>If this propaganda is working in somewhere much farther from the US and in a country much more progressive towards vaping than Canada, imagine what smokers think here. We have to make sure that we are doing what we can in order to spread the truth about vaping as an alternative to smoking, because public perception is directly connected to regulations. If we want to be able to vape what we want at a price that is reasonable, then spread this blog post and the truth.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/provincial-attacks-on-vaping-alberta-and-nova-scotia</id>
    <published>2020-02-23T10:56:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-19T10:58:21-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/provincial-attacks-on-vaping-alberta-and-nova-scotia"/>
    <title>Provincial Attacks on Vaping – Alberta and Nova Scotia</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Budget 2020 has been released by the Albertan government, and its looking like there is a focus on the vaping industry. They base it on research that points toward a 10 per cent hike in the price of tobacco having an effect of decreasing youth use by approximately the same amount.</p>
<p><br>The new tax will be a whopping 20 percent, to be charged on all eliquid, DIY vaping products and even cannabis vapes. In the first year alone, the government expect to net $4 million and in the second year it expects $8 million. This difference can be explained by both the costs associated with getting the message out and educating retailers as well as the ramp up for retailers to actually follow and remit these taxes.</p>
<p><br>While this new tax will have an effect on vapers, its is definitely not the worst regulations to come out. Nova Scotia for example, is introducing a $0.50 per millilitre tax! That works out to a whopping $30 extra on a 60ml bottle, bringing the average cost to between $55 to $60 per 60ml!</p>
<p><br>Nova Scotia is a prime example of the government following the whims of the Tobacco industry. They are making vaping much more expensive than smoking as well as making the tobacco industry’s vaping devices cheaper. Juul, Vype and other pod style devices are mainly sourced from tobacco companies, and the tax on them is only around $1.50 for a pack of 3 pods!</p>
<p><br>What this will do is either push people towards higher and higher nicotine content devices or steer them back to cigarettes. This is a blatant disservice to society and the people that suffer will be Nova Scotians themselves.</p>
<p><br>Back to the Albertan regulations, the UCP government is using this as its first step, so we can expect more rules to come out. At VanGo Vapes we constantly monitor the provincial and federal governments actions and we predict that the Albertan government will enact the following measures soon as well:</p>
<ul>
<li>Similar laws on vaping in public places to smoking – no vaping close to public entrances, windows or intakes.</li>
<li>Limits on the types and places that vape companies can market their products. Likely this will be limited to places where all ages are allowed like corner stores and gas stations.</li>
<li>There is a slight chance that there will be distance requirements for vaping stores to be a certain distance away from high schools and community centres, like some jurisdiction’s laws on marijuana retailers.</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Stay<span> </span>tuned for the next blog posts!</strong></em></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/are-anti-vaping-studies-propaganda</id>
    <published>2020-02-20T10:25:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T10:46:57-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/are-anti-vaping-studies-propaganda"/>
    <title>Are Anti Vaping Studies just a Propaganda?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p>Recently in the headlines, the USA’s best known tobacco researcher is <a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/JAHA.119.014519" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">retracting a study</a> that said that vaping doubled the risk of heart attacks. This paper, written by Bhatta and Glantz was removed from the Journal of the American Heart Association and was paid effectively a waste of $20 million dollars by the FDA and the National Institutes of Health.</p>
<p>This study was questioned back in July by USA TODAY and the researcher even noticed back then that most of the heart attacks happened before people even vaped!</p>
<p>It’s like taking a survey of bodies in a graveyard and concluding that the cause of death was being buried alive - obviously that's ridiculous.</p>
<p>This study was used many times to try and argue for stricter regulations on vaping and most likely convinced numerous people to abstain from vaping - making them continue to smoke. Even after the editors and numerous other scientists admitted that the study was very weak, Glantz continued to stand by the paper. </p>
<p>Michael Siegal, a professor of community health sciences at Boston University acknowledged this all by <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_ca/article/v74zny/a-major-study-that-fueled-national-vape-panic-has-been-retracted" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">stating </a>that “there is a profound anti-e-cigarette bias among tobacco-control researchers, and this is precisely what caused this fiasco." The misconception that many of these researchers have is seen in the population as well. The proportion of the population that believes that vaping is as bad or worse than vaping is rising, and unless more publicity is given to these retractions and studies that show the truth about vaping, scientists and the public will continue to cloud the truth and let generations to come suffer under the threat of tobacco.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/are-the-new-vaping-laws-unconstitutional</id>
    <published>2020-02-13T10:08:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T10:08:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/are-the-new-vaping-laws-unconstitutional"/>
    <title>Are the new vaping laws unconstitutional?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>With both the provincial and federal government creating a patchwork of legislation, it is obvious that the coordination was not there. This confusing web of regulations has created a very harsh climate for vaping and the vaping industry. More importantly, this is leading to an adverse effect to the possible health benefits of vaping on the population.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The Canadian Constitution Foundation will soon release a <a href="https://theccf.ca/canadian-vaping-law-overview-and-constitutional-issues/?fbclid=IwAR1krHKKDi85lzyjANHY5gAcrdWFqUyVO10hhLiPszPhCbMNfPgX7_it_5w" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">report </a>on the effect of vaping legislation on harm reduction, and how it has been modeled on anti smoking legislation. Punishment for breaking the rules can include imprisonment and these Draconian laws have succeeded in scaring much of the population.</div>
<div></div>
<div id="ext-gen312">With some of the potential and current laws putting restrictions on things like advertising, nicotine content and even flavour has caused vaping to become less effective and definitely less attainable. Smokers do not understand the truths nor are they able to come across them or information about vaping unless they personally know someone who already vapes. Being unable to claim the benefits as a supporter and member of the industry really steps on our goal of helping society.</div>
<div></div>
<div>In Canada, we have the right to not to be deprived of life, liberty and security of the person, unless it encroaches on the principles of fundamental justice. However when vaping laws over encroach on our lives, the government is taking a smokers' ability to make the switch to vaping and is depraving them of their rights to life and security. The right to life is deprived as making the switch lessens the chance of death &amp; the right to security is deprived because the benefit of switching is a positive boost for the general health of individuals.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The government has not stopped there. They've also obstructed our right to the freedom of expression. When manufacturers cannot market their products nor design them to reflect what they truly are, this restriction of our freedoms are a complete unnecessary encroachment on our rights, and should be fought.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This is just the beginning. While the government can take away our rights and make the public afraid of something that has the potential to help society, at least it's a sign that there is something deeper, more sinister at work. Politics playing with big money playing with the inclinations of old and unreasonable rhetoric has the potential to actually harm a good part of our population. This is only because they are too swayed by the untruths and too scared to reach for something better.</div>
<div></div>
<div id="ext-gen313">We will keep you posted on what the Canadian Constitution Foundation is doing to help our cause and how we can make vaping accessible to more smokers. With reasonable legislation, vaping has the potential to save countless lives and change the generations to come! </div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/5-accessories-every-vaper-needs</id>
    <published>2020-02-09T10:15:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T10:15:44-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/5-accessories-every-vaper-needs"/>
    <title>5 Accessories Every Vaper Needs</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>When you dropped your smokes for a vape, you went from being someone who always has a lighter, to someone who always has a paper towel.</div>
<div></div>
<div>So, as a vaper, what are some things you always have on hand? Some things that will save you lots of stress and trouble, and the basic essentials you should not be caught without...</div>
<div></div>
<ol>
<li><strong>Extra juice</strong></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>There are two types of vapers - those who only vape a specific juice all the time and those who jump around continuously. If you are someone who only vapes one juice, you have to make sure you always have extras! One tip in this regard is that when you are running down to the last little bit, you should stash it away. Put it in the glove compartment of your car or in your sock drawer, you'll thank us later!</li>
<li><strong>Extra Batteries / Battery Pack</strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>If you use 18650 batteries, you should always have a spare charged set with you. If your vape has a built in battery, make sure to have an external battery pack with you, or at least a wire you can plug in to an outlet. Sometimes in those mornings when you have to drag yourself out of bed, or those nights where you barely make it to the bed, you forget to switch the batteries or charge your vape and you will regret it if you don't have a backup!</li>
<li><strong>Extra Coils / Cotton</strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Whether you vape on a rebuild-able device or you use pre-built coils, you never know when you may accidentally burn it. A mistake as simple as forgetting to lock it when you put it in your pocket, you should always keep an extra coil with you. For those flavour chasers who use drippers or RDA's, you already know you must also carry at the very least some extra cotton, a pair of tweezers and a set of scissors.</li>
<li><strong>Microfiber Cloth</strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>One of the most annoying things about vaping in the car is the residue that builds up on all the glass surfaces, especially the windshield. Evaporated Vegetable Glycerin builds up extremely thick, and even the heater on full blast wont get rid of the buildup. Make sure to have at least one clean microfiber cloth with you in the car at all times to rub away the fog!</li>
<li><strong>Carrying Case</strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Finally, to carry all of these essentials around, it would be good to have a handy carrying case available. You should look for something with many pockets and small enough that it wont be too bulky to carry it around or hide it under your seat in the car. There are even a few bag brands that cater specifically to vapers, like UD or Coilmaster, with special places for everything you need from batteries to scissors!</li>
</ul>
<div id="ext-gen325"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/what-is-the-ohm-s-law-and-how-does-this-effect-you</id>
    <published>2020-01-30T10:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T10:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/what-is-the-ohm-s-law-and-how-does-this-effect-you"/>
    <title>What is Ohm’s Law? How does this affect you?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The ohm’s law is a law stating electrical current is proportional to voltage and inversely proportional to resistance.</p>
<p>The higher the ohm rating, the more resistance it has. In your atomizer, "more resistance = less" power through the battery to the tip of your tank. High ohms requires higher voltage to heat the coils up at the same rate. This means it takes longer to ramp the heat up to vaporizing temperature. Lower ohms means lesser wait time and instant vape. Atomizers have different ohm ratings because each device has different voltage. Different ohms can change your vaping experience through flavor and intensity. <br><br>It is important to be informed on ohms ratings and the laws surrounding them. We often hear of devices “exploding” in the media and this is giving vaping a bad name!</p>
<p>This is due to lack of education! <strong>It is actually the batteries exploding due to the overflow of electricity.</strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Stay educated and tuned for the next blog posts!</strong></em></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/a-history-of-the-types-of-vaping-devices</id>
    <published>2020-01-23T10:40:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T10:54:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/a-history-of-the-types-of-vaping-devices"/>
    <title>A History of the Types of Vaping Devices Part 3</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Generation 2 - The Cartomizer</p>
<p> </p>
<div id="ext-gen345">After the idea of vaporizing a liquid containing nicotine was a public idea, it was time for the free market to take reigns and for better ideas to arise. Umer and Tariq Sheikh took the idea and <a href="https://stevevape.com/what-does-the-future-hold-for-vaping-technology/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">integrated a heating coil</a> into the chamber holding the liquid solution.
<p>This was the same technology that brands like Kanger used in their devices, and is basically the same principle behind almost all modern day vapes.</p>
<div>Around the same time, Joyetech entered the market and thought up the standardized 510 connection. They, along with most manufacturers in the marked styled the ecigs to resemble a cigarette, hence the name that was given to it called the "cigalike".
<p>The first mainstream products that came out borne from these ideas was called eGo vaporizer. The Joyetech eGo-T was released which biased the ability not only to be modular in the sense that a user could swap tanks, mouthpieces and the battery unit, but it was also refillable and when the atomizer burnt out, they could just change the coil and it would be good as new.</p>
<p>This specific technology is still used today in most vapes, the main difference between them all is the makeup of the coil and the wicking material. Simply put, all modern day e-cigs have a battery for power, a metal coil (stainless steel, nichrome, kanthal etc), a wicking material which is usually cotton, and a tank or some sort of reservoir to contain the liquid.</p>
<p> </p>
<div id="ext-gen346">After this point, the new innovations in the industry were much more incremental however with every year that goes by vapes become more economical and efficient. After this point as well, the types of devices split into 2, with some people building coils themselves and the rest using pre-built coils. Stay tuned to learn about the flavourful world of manually built / rebuild-able coils!</div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/a-history-of-the-types-of-vaping-devices-1</id>
    <published>2020-01-12T10:54:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T10:59:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/a-history-of-the-types-of-vaping-devices-1"/>
    <title>A History of the Types of Vaping Devices Part 2</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Generation 1 - Ultrasonic Vaporizers<br><br>The man who has been credited with the modern day vape is a Chinese man named Hon Lik, whose father died from lung cancer caused by cigarettes. This was in 2003 and this pharmacist had something that would change the lives of millions - and he knew it.<br><br>By 2007, e-cigarettes had been introduced to Europe and the United States, and the first commercial vapes were in use. The design was based around a battery powering an ultrasound vaporizer, rather than a heating element that most vapes nowadays are made of.<br><br>The device used very high frequency sound waves which would vibrate the liquid inside a tank to a certain level which would essentially convert the liquid to a gas. One stark difference about this method of vaporizing, is that the vapor that comes out is almost as cool as the liquid itself; there is no heating.<br><br></p>
<p><a href="http://www.healthnz.co.nz/Ruyan_ecigarette.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/image002_large.jpg?v=1597945948" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></a></p>
<p><br>This first generation vape was not well received by the public, but it was a start in the right direction. Hon Lik had triggered a wave of ingenuity, and the company he worked for called Ruyan (the name was later changed to Dragonite International) was eventually sold to Imperial Tobacco in 2013. This was just the beginning, and over the years vaping devices changed and developed to become what we see today...</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-first-vape-ever-made</id>
    <published>2020-01-09T11:03:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T11:11:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/the-first-vape-ever-made"/>
    <title>The First Vape Ever Made</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>It may surprise you, but the first vaping device was invented even before you might have even been born!</p>
<p><br>Back in 1963, a scrap metal dealer named <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/innovation/plans-for-first-e-cigarette-went-up-in-smoke-50-years-ago-180970730/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Herbert A. Gilbert</a><span> </span> patented the "Smokeless" - essentially the first vape invented. The 60's were the beginning of an eternal campaign on the negatives of smoking cigarettes, and the possibility of a substitute to such a ubiquitous vice had Herbert thinking hard about the income potential.</p>
<p><br>Similar to today's vaping market, he created flavors that would appeal to the masses in order to help the conversion with tastes like mint, rum and cinnamon!<br>Unfortunately the invention was ahead of its time and Herbert couldn't find a company to produce the design and the patent's exclusivity ran out long before the comeback in the early 2000's and look where we are today.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1054/0238/files/The_First_Ecig_grande.jpg?v=1597946552" alt=""></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/what-to-expect-in-the-new-year-for-vaping</id>
    <published>2020-01-05T11:41:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T11:48:34-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/what-to-expect-in-the-new-year-for-vaping"/>
    <title>What to expect in the new year for vaping?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[2020 will be a year like no other in regards to the vaping industry as a whole across the world. This year we have already seen the US government crack down and ban sales of mint and fruit flavor pod devices, and that is just the beginning. By May this year, all US manufacturers of vaping products will have to have made their submission to the FDA under under a PMTA sumbission or else be at risk for breaking the law. <br><br>In Canada, provinces are expected to create more laws and the begining of it all is BC. We have already <a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/2019/11/new-british-columbia-vaping-regulations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seen what is to come including the now 25% tax</a>, but this is just the begining. Other provinces like Alberta will release their regulations soon, and it is expected to be close to BC's. <br><br>However on the bright side, more longer term studies are coming to light that show that vaping is effective in helping people stop smoking cigarettes. In an <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/health-50813226" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">article from the BBC</a> on 2019's biggest breakthrough, vaping was listed as something that is helping people make the switch. The article quoted a <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/10.1056/NEJMoa1808779" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">study</a> in the <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/10.1056/NEJMoa1808779" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">New England Journal of Medicine</a> that concluded that "E-cigarettes were more effective for smoking cessation than nicotine-replacement therapy" as "the 1-year abstinence rate was 18.0% in the e-cigarette group, as compared with 9.9% in the nicotine-replacement group." <br><br>In all, while the regulations will get more stringent to come, we predict that the image of vaping will get better over time because of the proofs that are coming out. We expect 2020 to have a lot of vaping updates to come, so make sure to keep up with whats going on by subscribing to our newsletter at the bottom of this page!]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/5-things-canadian-vape-stores-need-to-know</id>
    <published>2019-11-27T12:47:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T13:41:36-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/5-things-canadian-vape-stores-need-to-know"/>
    <title>5 things Canadian vape stores need to know!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>With the vaping industry now a regulated industry in Canada, there are now regulators coming around making sure stores are only stocking and promoting products in a compliant way. Although from province to province and even city to city there are different laws and different levels of enforcement based on the officer in your region, by following these steps you should be trouble free<br><br>Characters on bottles or marketing materials</p>
<p><br>According to Bill S5, section 30.‍21 states that no testimonials are allowed, and that includes depictions of characters, real or fictitious. What this means is that if anything you sell has any animals, faces or anything that resembles a character, you cannot stock it. What many vape store owners are doing is covering up the characters (such as the falcon on the Horizon Falcontech Tank) with white stickers and selling them like that.</p>
<p><br>Recently there was a store who had a big cardboard popup promoting a juice brand with monkeys on it, and the store manager was asked to get rid of it by the compliance officer. This shows that not only are your products going to be examined, but also your marketing materials such as banners, posters and the like.</p>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Disallowed flavours or descriptions</strong></li>
</ol><ul>
<li>In Bill S5, all flavours that can be interpreted as a confectionary, dessert, energy drink, soft drink or marijuana flavour is not allowed. For example calling a Custard a Kustard doesn't work; there has to be room for interpretation. This doesn't only apply to the flavour name but also the description, whether it's on the bottle, on some marketing material in store or a product online.</li>
</ul>
<li><strong>Secret shoppers coming in</strong></li>
<ul>
<li>One of a vape stores biggest fear is to sell products to an underage person. This can cause huge backlash from the vaping industry as well as fines from the government. It seems pretty obvious to ID anyone that looks underage but this can also be a problem as some people physically develop faster, and someone can come in looking older than they are. The best practice used in most locations is to ID anyone that looks under 30. Sure, you may offend a small number of people, however that is just the cost of staying in business.</li>
<li>One big mistake that many shop owners and employees do is ID the customer when they are buying something, however this is actually not the right way to do things. A vape store can put up posters and promote their products only because youth are not able to see it, so this means that vape stores must ID the person as soon as they walk in.</li>
</ul>
<li><strong>Customers vaping in store</strong></li>
<ul>
<li>This is something that differs from region to region so take care to understand any provincial or municipal bylaws that effect you. For example in BC, only 2 people are allowed to vape at one time in a store, and only for testing purposes. No staff or anyone hanging out can test. Although again it depends on how strict your enforcement officer is, try to be on top of this.</li>
</ul>
<li><strong>Online Sales need to be age verified</strong></li>
<ul>
<li>Many stores have an online presence, and if you do make sure that your website has an age verification system as well as the delivery company you use. While Canada Post offers age verification and signature services, they only do that in Canada and it doesnt work with PO boxes. The best company to use for this would probably be UPS as they can ask for age verification even if you are shipping to the US.</li>
</ul>
<ol></ol>
<br>In all, it doesn't take much besides staying vigilant to be compliant these days. Having problems with regulations and regulators can cost you a lot of time and money, so work with these basic points and you should be fine. Of course, as stated before each jurisdiction may have extra rules that you should know about but the above are the main ones. If you have any questions or additions to the above list, let us know!
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vaping-laws-in-japan</id>
    <published>2019-11-06T13:47:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-20T13:47:19-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vaping-laws-in-japan"/>
    <title>Vaping Laws in Japan</title>
    <author>
      <name>Ray Aquino</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong><em>Is Vaping Legal in Japan?</em></strong><br><br>Simply put, vaping is legal in Japan. Although it is not as common as other countries like Canada, the USA and the UK, it is starting to become more popular as people switch from cigarettes.<br><br> Where can you buy vape juice in Japan?<br><br>Across Japan in cities like Tokyo, Osaka, Kyoto and others, there are more and more people starting to vape through vape stores that are popping up just like most other countries. The problem that arises however is that in Japan, there are very strict rules on selling and purchasing nicotine eliquid.<br><br>Liquid nicotine that is used in e liquid is pharmaceutical substance in Japan so if you want to buy locally, only pharmacists can sell it (as of now, no pharmacists sell it). Basically it is illegal to sell nicotine ejuice in japan,,,<br><br>However fortunately that law does not mean it is illegal to buy eliquid containing nicotine in Japan. According to the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare &lt;https://www.mhlw.go.jp/english/policy/health-medical/pharmaceuticals/01.html&gt; in Japan, you can actually bring in a 1 month supply of nicotine eliquid. This not only applies to if you are coming into Japan but also importing it from out of country. What the Japan Customs agency considers 1 month supply to be is 120ml of juice.<br><br>VanGo Vapes ships nicotine containing eliquid regularly to Japan. We ship both freebase and salt nicotine to Japanese customers from all over the country, and have had resounding success at it. As long as you are importing up to 120ml of liquid, you are good. <br><br>How long does it take to ship ejuice to Japan?<br><br>Typically it will take 3 to 5 days for the e juice to reach the vaper in Japan. VanGo Vapes uses UPS for most of the deliveries, so you can be certain you will get it. There may be a customs delay as with anything coming from out of the country so make sure to plan ahead. <br><br>What type of vape flavors are popular in Japan?<br><br>According to our data, the most popular e liquid flavors in Japan are Menthol, Fruits, Tobacco's and then Creams. Make sure to check out VanGo Vapes' selection of over 80 different flavours of liquids and contact us if you have any questions!]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vaping-vacations-mexico</id>
    <published>2019-08-07T08:07:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-07T08:07:33-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vaping-vacations-mexico"/>
    <title>Vaping Vacations: Mexico</title>
    <author>
      <name>VanGo Vapes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="p1"><span data-contrast="auto">Mexico is a large country with a lot to offer</span><span data-contrast="auto">;</span><span data-contrast="auto"> great food, interesting history, creative arts and crafts, </span><span data-contrast="auto">exciting</span><span data-contrast="auto"> sporting events and of course, beautiful beaches. Some of the biggest, </span><span data-contrast="auto">Tulum, Cancun, Punta Cana, </span><span data-contrast="auto">and</span><span data-contrast="auto"> Cozumel,</span><span data-contrast="auto"> draw thousands of tourists from all over the world.</span><span data-contrast="auto"> Mexico has a beach for any type of experience you’re looking for.</span><span data-ccp-props='{"201341983":0,"335559739":160,"335559740":259}'> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">There are secluded beaches that offer privacy and quiet, surrounded by ancient ruins and jungles. Some offer calm water and sandy shores that are perfect for swimming. Mexico is a snorkeler</span><span data-contrast="auto">’s</span><span data-contrast="auto"> paradise</span><span data-contrast="auto"> with exquisite and colourful coral reefs that also offer much to scuba divers. Perfect white sands line many of the beaches where travelers can enjoy paddleboarding and kayaking. Some people prefer to be out on the water, sailing, deep-sea fishing or looking to spot some whales.</span><span data-ccp-props='{"201341983":0,"335559739":160,"335559740":259}'> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Topical fruit is available all over, often from street vendors located near the beaches and in the towns. Mango, guava, pomegranate and </span><span data-contrast="auto">cactus fruit </span><span data-contrast="auto">are some of the most familiar to foreign travelers. We’ve captured the romance of the beach with a fruity mixture of jackfruit and mango with undertones of lychee, strawberry and cactus fruit</span><span data-contrast="auto">. Flavours that transport you to a culturally rich tropical paradise.</span><span data-ccp-props='{"201341983":0,"335559739":160,"335559740":259}'> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">As to the rules, you can vape in Mexico but importing e-cigarettes is strictly prohibited. So only bring what you need as to not be suspected </span><span data-contrast="auto">of</span><span data-contrast="auto"> illegal trafficking, but at the same time it is difficult to find retailers of e-juice so you’ll need to bring enough.</span><span data-ccp-props='{"201341983":0,"335559739":160,"335559740":259}'> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">If you ever get tired of the beachgoers paradise there are many exciting things to do. </span><span data-contrast="auto">Many of the towns and cities have an extensive selection of restaurants, cafes, and bars along with a vibrant nightlife. But the enjoyment of Mexico isn’t just limited to those that are currently there. Bring back the memories or have a taste of the experience</span><span data-contrast="auto"> while enjoying a vaping vacation with Cactus </span><span data-contrast="auto">Jango.</span><span data-ccp-props='{"201341983":0,"335559739":160,"335559740":259}'> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #f3f3f3;"><button type="button"><a href="https://www.vangovapes.com/products/cactus-jango?variant=4060150595613" style="color: #f3f3f3;">Buy Now</a></button></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/epic-road-trip-the-grand-canyon</id>
    <published>2019-07-28T18:51:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-28T18:51:17-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/epic-road-trip-the-grand-canyon"/>
    <title>Epic Road Trip: The Grand Canyon</title>
    <author>
      <name>VanGo Vapes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[The Grand Canyon should be a stop of any epic road trip because it is indeed epic. Located in Arizona, this colorful and immense canyon is 446 km long, 29 km wide and 1.6 km deep. Famous for its multi-colored rock formations which are created by trace amounts of minerals and result in the red, yellow and green coloring of the canyon walls. It’s a lot like our Jango Chill flave with its colorful mix of mango, jackfruit, strawberries, cactus and lychee with hints of mint and vanilla. <br><br>Unfortunately, it is a very popular destination, especially during the summer. More than six million people a year come through, taking in the views, trails, mule trips, white water rafting, train tours and helicopter rides. It’s a good idea to arrive before 9:00 am to beat the crowds. <br>
<h3>The South Rim</h3>
Open year-round, this is the main starting point for most visitors. With hotels, bus service and water stations it is the most developed part of the park. Some of the best views are Pipe Creek Vista and Yavapai Point. Both are great spots the enjoy some flavor and a deep vape. <br>
<h3>The North Rim</h3>
Over 320 km away, the North Rim is less busy and only open part of the year. It’s also 304.8 m higher, (that’s about 1000 feet), which makes a big difference in climate and vegetation. The slight bite to the air in the evenings echoes the chill in Jango Chill. <br>
<h3>Bright Angel Trail</h3>
Starting from the South Rim, this trail is the safest way into the canyon and provides amenities like shade structures, emergency phones, toilets and water stations. It heads down through a variety of switchbacks for over 7 km and includes a suspension bridge over the Colorado River. This is the oldest trail in the park and the one originally followed by Native Americans and prospectors. <br>
<h3>Skywalk at Eagle Point</h3>
This attraction is not for the faint of heart or those terrified by heights. The Skywalk is a horseshoe-shaped walkway of glass over 1200 meters above the canyon floor,(that’s 4000 feet) on the Hualapai Indian Reservation. Open since 2007, it’s for those who think standing on the edge of a cliff doesn’t' provide enough of a view. <br>
<h3>Star gazing</h3>
Since most of us live in concentrated population areas, light pollution prevents us from getting an accurate view of the night sky. Starting in 2016 the Grand Canyon began changing exterior lights to limit light pollution and meet International Dark Sky Park certification and now it is a beautiful spot to watch a sunset fade into a natural night sky. <br><br>The great thing about an e-cigarette in a place like the Grand Canyon is that there is no fire risk like that which comes with traditional cigarettes, meaning you don’t have to worry when the park implements smoking bans in times of increased dryness. <br><br>We have more stops on our Epic Road Trip ahead and more flavors to explore.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vape-care-in-the-summer</id>
    <published>2019-07-28T18:32:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-28T18:32:32-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vangovapes.com/blogs/blog/vape-care-in-the-summer"/>
    <title>Vape Care in the Summer</title>
    <author>
      <name>VanGo Vapes</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[The days are ticking away, but there is still time for summer adventures. From the beach to camping, patio parties and road trips, there are a few things to think about if you will be vaping. <br><br>If you’re taking any trips this summer it’s important you are aware of the regulations involving vape products, both with your form of travel and the location you plan to visit. The rules change from city to city as well as among states, provinces or countries. <br>
<h3>Flying with your Vape</h3>
In Canada and the U.S., you can bring your device and e-juice on a plane, but it must not be in your checked baggage; it is allowed in your carry-on only! Your juice follows the same rules as other liquids, which need to be stored in clear bottles of 100ml or less and sealed in a plastic bag. Your total combined liquids must be under a liter, so you might be able to bring only a limited number of flavors with you. <br>
<h3>Other Tips for Flying</h3>
<ul>
<li>You can pack additional liquids in your checked baggage if you need more flaves.</li>
<li>Disconnect the battery from the device before boarding.</li>
<li>The pressure change in the air can cause your tank to leak, so either empty your tank before you leave or store it in a plastic bag.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Sunny Days</h3>
Traditionally, summer means warmer weather and lots of sun. These are two things that your e-juice and tanks are not fond of. Do not leave them sitting in a hot car or direct sunlight. E-juices start to break down at around 40C. This can change the viscosity and color and really does a number on the flavor. And the nicotine breaks down. These are permeant changes, so cooling them down again won’t reverse the damage. When facing a day in the sun, store your juices in a cooler to enjoy them as they are meant to be. Heat and sun are bad for the batteries as well. <br>
<h3>Car adapter and charging kits</h3>
Many people enjoy a good vape on their camping trip or hiking adventure. Just remember that it is an electronic device, and the batteries will only last so long. To keep the batteries charged, we suggest bringing along a car adapter or a charging kit. If you have to, you can usually use your phone charger to keep you going. <br>
<h3>Swimming and vaping</h3>
Yes, you can vape and swim, but not with any old e-cigarette. There are special devices that are waterproof and shockproof, letting you vape while sitting in a floaty on the water without any worries. Go online and check out the many reviews to find the best waterproof option for your needs. <br>
<h3>Places you can’t vape this summer</h3>
E-cigarettes and smoking are generally regulated under the same rules. So if you can’t smoke somewhere, that usually means no vaping either. You can’t vape on planes, inside restaurants or near playgrounds. Most hotels and car rental agencies also forbid vaping. But the rules are different in every municipality, so do your research. In some places you can vape on patios or in restaurants and bars, in others you can’t vape in parks or at the beach. <br><br>The age limits are also different based on where you go. Usually the minimum age for buying vaping products ranges from 18 to 21. And as of this summer, you can’t buy or vape anywhere in San Francisco. It’s the first city to ban vaping in the USA, but others are looking at the option, so check the news before you plan a trip just in case! <br><br>Enjoy a flavorful summer!]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
